MONALISA CHATTERJEE

monalisa.chatterjee.us@gmail.com | 470 312 4606| Maryville MO 64468 | linkedin.com/in/monachatterj | bit.ly/resume_mona

PROFILE SUMMARY

Graduate student with 6 years of experience in data visualization in Qlikview, Tableau, Power BI and ETL (Datastage) tools. Adaptive in using any BI Tools and possessing data analytics skills. Coded in programming languages such as C, Java and Python basics. Proficient knowledge and firsthand experience in Dataware housing, Data Analysis & Modelling, PL/SQL, MySQL, Microsoft suit (proficient in MS excel). Possess extensive knowledge of SQL along with its variation for popular database like Oracle 12c and MySQL databases for 5 years.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Systems
Northwest Missouri State University-Maryville, MO
Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication

Jun 2013 | GPA 3.36/4.0

Dec 2020 | GPA 4.0/4.0

Bengal College of Engineering and Technology

SKILLS

Languages: C, Java, MySQL, PL/SQL, Python basics

Tools: NetBeans IDE, Cognos, Rapid Miner, Tableau, Qlikview, DataStage, Power BI, MS office suit.

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Assistant
Northwest Missouri State University

Jan 2020 – Present

Business Intelligence Developer

Tech Mahindra, Hyderabad, India

Audit and Assurance (Qlikview Developer):

Jan 2014 – Jun 2019 Dec 2016 – Jun 2019

- Awarded "Star award" for performance in 2017. Awarded "Certificate of Excellence" in work in 2019.
- Modeled and deployed Qlikview applications with required KPIs to track planned, actual audits and to analyse the data integrity of the audited data. Reduced Data Integrity issues by 80%.
- Designed 50+ dashboards for Audit and Assurance application. Enhanced around 100+ existing reports in Qlikview as a part of problem fixes and new functionalities.

Ticketing report Automation (Power BI Developer):

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

- Designed and implemented Power BI dashboards to reduce efforts to analyze ticketing reports.
- Automated Power BI reports to fetch live data from the incident, Problem ticketing tool that is Remedy and for change requests from Pandora. This reduced the efforts drastically by 150% by ticket report automation for GlaxoSmithKline.

SCAT (Tableau Developer)

May 2015 - Dec 2016

- Remodeled existing data model and customer requirement to implement changes in the existing Tableau reporting system. Fixed daily issues in data visualization reports and performed root cause analysis. The enhancements increased the performance by 60% for GlaxoSmithKline.
- Troubleshoot daily issues and performed root cause analysis in case of report distribution failure.

Sales Force Application (Application Support Engineer)

Jun 2014 - May 2015

- Brainstormed to oversee data related issues and provide quick workarounds to fix problem Fixed daily issues in ETL (Datastage) and performed root cause analysis in case failure.
- Awarded "Associate of the Month" for showing great dedication and managing complex data visualization application in 2014.
- Managed service request from clients. Resolved data related issues. Championed in Service Request handling by handling around 20-30 tickets per week.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS (Northwest Missouri State University):

- Capstone Project: Built data inventory for Second harvest food management system.
- Project Management project: Managed team building, teamwork management through Trello and MS project
 2016 to acquire software and hardware on behalf of client.